Guide to the University File Reference Collection, 1960-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
University File reference collection 1960-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
2.5 Linear Feet approx. 2000 Items
The University File Reference Collection contains files of memoranda, clippings, brochures, booklets, proposals, reports, and other documents by or about the University's non-academic administrative offices and divisions. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The University File Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
The University File Reference Collection contains files of memoranda, clippings, brochures, booklets, proposals, reports, and other documents by or about the University's administrative offices, divisions, and other non-academic and non-research units. The collection is arranged topically: central administration; accounting and business; safety and security; technology and telecommunications; miscellaneous offices. It includes materials about defunct units the responsibilities of which were absorbed by other units.
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List
  - Administration - articles and memoranda (Box 1)
  - Administration - listings
  - Administration - organization charts
  - Administration - studies and reports
  - President - Duke Dimensions [magazine], January, 1981
  - President - Duke University Letters, 1979-1985
  - President - How to Think Straight Series, #1-#24, 1982-1985
  - President - Memoranda and reports, 1962-1970
  - President - President’s Associates, circa 1973-1976
  - President - The President’s Letter, 1970-1979
  - President - Report of Scholarly Activities, 1979
  - Chancellor, 1968, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Chancellor A. K. Pye - Retrenchment - clippings, 1980-1982
  - Provost - history of the office
  - Provost - Institutional Research Report, 1993
  - Provost - International Programs, 1996
  - Provost - Memoranda, reports, etc. 1962-1995 (5 folders)
  - Provost - Strategic plans, 2000-
  - Deans, 1967-
  - Vice-President for Business and Finance, 1964, 1980
  - Vice-President for Institutional Advancement - The Third Side of the Triangle [1969]
  - Vice-President for Planning and Institutional Studies, reports and memoranda, 1964-1966
  - Registrar - History, 1977-
  - Registrar - Schedule of Courses, 2001 Summer and Fall
  - Registrar - Statistics: number of degrees awarded, 1926-1994
  - Registrar - Student records: policies and systems, 1969-1995
  - Treasurer, 1959-1979
  - University Counsel - history
  - Patent Office, 1979-
  - Administrative Notes [newsletter], 1981-1983 (Box 3)
  - Accounting - Clippings
  - Accounting - The Bottom Line [newsletter], 1997/98
  - Accounting Systems codebook, 1997 (4 folders
  - Bursar, 1972-1989
  - Controller, 1975-1990
  - Cost Reduction Office, 1969-
  - Internal Audit, 1963-1994
  - Purchasing Department, 1965-1970
  - Sponsored Programs Office, 1983-1990, undated
  - Safety & security - Memoranda, 1960- (Box 4)
  - Safety & security - Department of Security. Safety Report, 1971
  - Safety & security - Safety Office, 1972-1993
  - Safety & security - Clippings, 1975-
  - Safety & security - Public Safety Department. Police Operations Manual, 1977-1979
  - Safety & security - Duke Public Safety. Community Safety Report, 1989-1998
  - Safety & security - Cycling at Duke, [1990-1995]
  - Safety & security - Occupational and Environmental Safety Office, 1993-
  - Safety & security - Occupational and Environmental Safety Office, newsletter, 1994-
  - Safety & security - Duke University Police Department. Publications, ca. 1997-
  - Telecommunications – clippings, 1965-1995
  - Telecommunications – flyers and brochures, undated
  - Telecommunications – memoranda, 1965-1991
  - Duke University Communications Proposal / General Telephone, 1965
  - Duke Tel-Com / Norman H. Sefton, Director, July, 1977 [Report]
  - North Carolina Utilities Commission, Docket P-112, Testimony and exhibits in re: Joint Petition of Duke Telephone Company and Duke University to Provide Telephone Service at Duke University, [1973] (Box 5)
  - Management Information Services, undated, [1980s]
  - Telecommunications - Tel-Com Update [newsletter], 1988-1993
  - Computer Assist Center, 1992-1995
  - Office of Information Technology, 1997-
  - Office of Information Technology- Glove Box News [ newsletter] 2000-2002
  - Facilities – Proposal: Roadway & Parking Area Grading / Boney & Newcomb, 1959
  - Facilities, 1970-
  - Facilities, clippings, 1973-
  - Instrument Shop, undated
  - Material Support Department, memoranda
  - Material Support Department, publications, 1996, undated
  - Material Support Department, clippings, 1971-1995
  - Office of Institutional Equity/Affirmative Action, 1971-
  - Special Events Office, 1962-
  - Translation Service, 1975: The Finnish Sauna/ Dr. Antti Arstila
  - Typing Bureau, 1955-1973